Guide to the Records of the Department of French Literature, Thought and Culture RG.37.13
New York University Archives
- La Maison Française Sound Recordings, 1966-1999
  - Finas, Lucette: "Dénouer: Balzac et Flaubert", January 30, 1990; cuid18482 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0148)
    Duration: 63 minutes; Preservation Note: Severe sound/speed distortion at the beginning of Side 1.
  - Roubichou, Gérard: "Discours parodique et discours romanesque en relisant Queneau", February 8, 1990; cuid18483 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0149)
    Duration: 72 minutes; Preservation Note: Skips in audio at the beginning of Side 2.
  - Nesci, Catherine: "Inter Mimologiques Nodier, dériseur sensé?", February 27, 1990; cuid18484 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0150)
  - Apostolides, Jean-Marie: "Mai 68 et la modernité", March 1, 1990; cuid18485 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0151)
    Duration: 64 minutes
  - Doubrovsky, Serge: "En dialogue avec Tom Bishop (Chair, Dept. of French, NYU: Le Livre brisé: un roman à deux)", April 3, 1990; cuid18486 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0152)
  - Green, André: "Des Mouches aux Mots: Sartre et la psychanalyse", April 12, 1990; cuid18487 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0153)
    Duration: 48 minutes; Preservation Note: Side 2 only 30 seconds long, and has some skips in the audio content
  - Genette, Gérard: "La définition du style", April 17, 1990; cuid18488 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0154)
  - Yampolsky, Mikhail: "Questions au cinéma soviétique contemporain", November 5, 1990; cuid18489 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0155)
  - Prendergast, Christopher: "Circulating in the (pre/post) Modern City: from Jules Laforgue to Michel de Certeau", November 19, 1990; cuid18490 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0156)
    Duration: 88 minutes
  - Bernstein, Richard: "France: Why Fragile, Why Glorious?", January 24, 1991; cuid18491 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0157)
    Duration: 49 minutes; Preservation Note: Loud "pops" and speed issues on Side 2.
  - Scharfman, Ronnie: "Rewriting the Césaires: Caribbean Discoure in Daniel Maximin's L'Isolé Soleil", January 31, 1991; cuid18492 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0158)
  - Mitterand, Henri: "Poétique de l'espace romaneque: La bête humaine d'Emile Zola", February 12, 1991; cuid18493 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0159)
  - Tannery, Claude: "Malraux, l'art, la mort et la vie", February 20, 1991; cuid18494 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0160)
  - Zink, Michel: "Autour des chansons du XVe siècle: le traditionnel et le populaire", March 5, 1991; cuid18495 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0161)
  - Gaillard, Françoise: "Barthes: une vie", March 7, 1991; cuid18496 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0162)
    Duration: 89 minutes
  - Laurent, Jacques: "Le roman?", March 19, 1991; cuid18497 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0163)
    Duration: 65 minutes
  - Fleutiaux, Pierrette: "Nous sommes éternels", September 29, 1992; cuid18498 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0164)
  - Weber, Eugen: "Was Renan wrong? Reflections on the Use of Obsolete Ideas", May 7, 1991; cuid18499 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0165)
  - Cixous, Hélène: "Quelle heure est-il? Discussion in French of theoretical problems", September 29, 1992; cuid18500 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0166)
  - Foucault Roundtable, February 9, 1993; cuid18501 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0167)
  - Brooks, Peter, February 25, 1993; cuid18502 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0168)
    Duration: 84 minutes; Preservation Note: Second half of side 1 and first half of side 2 has a background noise that sounds like electronic interference
  - Fassin, Eric, April 14, 1994; cuid18503 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0169)
  - Bruckner, Pascal: "Yugoslavia: Europe Faces its Old Demons (Florence Gould Lecture)", September 15, 1994; cuid18504 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0170)
  - Chatelet, Noëlle: "Manger: un langage d'un corps (Florence Gould Lecture)", September 20, 1994; cuid18505 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0171)
  - Finas, Lucette: "Du goût à la lettre: Brillat-Savarin et Huysmans", September 22, 1994; cuid18506 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0172)
  - Cone, Michèle: "Max Jacob and his artistic circle (Galler Talk)", October 4, 1994; cuid18507 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0173)
  - Butor, Michel: "Après le roman (American Society of the French Legion of Honor Lecture)", October 6, 1994; cuid18508 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0174)
  - Vitz, Evelyn: "Reading, Telling, Playing, Singing! Medieval Romance in Performance (Co-sponsored with the Medieval and Renaissance Studies Program)", October 24, 1994; cuid18509 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0175)
    Duration: 28 minutes; Preservation Note: Side 1: 00:01:23 - 00:13:34 - unrelated English language content heard very faintly in left channel only. Side 2: 00:00:00 - 00:00:32 - unrelated English language content heard very faintly in left channel only. Both were left in the master files, but deleted from the access.
  - Hersant, Yves: "Voyageurs des lumières: sur les routes d'Europe au dix-huitième siècle", November 8, 1994; cuid18510 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0176)
    Duration: 83 minutes; Preservation Note: Side 2: 00:00:00;xx - 00:17:41;xx -- Different content, in English, regarding James Joyce; kept in the access file
  - Milner, Max: "Les dispositifs voyeuristes dans le récit balzacien", November 29, 1994; cuid18511 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0177)
  - Condé, Maryse: "Lectures de textes et discussions en français", February 13, 1995; cuid18512 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0178)
  - Badinter, Robert: "Center for French Civilization and Culture", February 17, 1995; cuid18513 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0179)
  - Debray, Régis: "Pour une histoire du regard en Occident", February 21, 1995; cuid18514 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0180)
  - Finkielkraut, Alain: "Le Destin de la culture", February 28, 1995; cuid18515 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0181)
  - Gaillard, Françoise: "Proust et le temps perdu", March 2, 1995; cuid18516 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0182)
  - Poiret-Delpech, Bertrand: "Culture et barbarie (Florence Gould Lecture)", March 7, 1995; cuid18517 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0183)
  - Scarpetta, Guy: "Kundera, auteur français", March 9, 1995; cuid18518 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0184)
  - Grumbach, Antoine: "Ville et architecture: la dialectique des contraintes (in French and English)", March 30, 1995; cuid18519 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0185)
  - Prigent, Christian: "Lectures de textes", April 11, 1995; cuid18520 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0186)
  - Roger, Philippe: "Le dernier des libertins", April 18, 1995; cuid18521 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0187)
    Duration: 87 minutes
  - Ashbery, John and Martory, Pierre (écrivain, poète): "Bi-lingual reading of Martory's poems with translations by Ashbery", April 24, 1995; cuid18522 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0188)
  - Dupin, Marc Olivier: "Le Conservatoire et la Cité de la Musique", April 25, 1995; cuid18523 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0189)
    Duration: 70 minutes
  - Arrabel, Fernando: "Les titans se meurent...Vive le théâtre!" (Florence Gould Lecture), May 2, 1995; cuid18524 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0190)
  - Biancotti, Hector: "D'une Langue à l'autre: une expérience littéraire", May 3, 1995; cuid18525 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0191)
  - Nimier, Marie: "Comment j'ai écrit certains de mes livres", May 4, 1995; cuid18526 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0192)
  - Robbe-Grillet, Alain: "Littérature et correction politique", September 19, 1995; cuid18527 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0193)
  - Dramé, Kandioura: "Il était un fois...l'Afrique latine" (co-sponsored with Africana Studies Program), September 21, 1995; cuid18528 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37-13.0194)
  - Kurtz, Maurice: "Copeau: the Revolt of Dramatic Art in Paris and New York", October 10, 1995; cuid18529 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0195)
    Note on cassette says "incomplete"
  - Pennac, Daniel: "Lectures de textes et discussion en français", October 30, 1995; cuid18530 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0196)
  - Favier, Jean: "Une Bibliothèque pour le troisème millénaire" (Florence Gould Lecture), October 31, 1995; cuid18531 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0197)
  - Serres, Michel: "Science et culture à l'orée de ce siècle" (Florence Gould Lecture), November 2, 1995; cuid18532 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0198)
  - Ben Jelloun, Tahar: "Le rôle de l'écrivain dans les pays du sud", November 14, 1995; cuid18533 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0199)
  - Dezon Jones, Elyane: "An Annotated Reading of Murder chez Proust", November 21, 1995; cuid18534 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0200)
    Duration: 51 minutes
  - Roger, Philippe: "Roland furieux et amoureux: Barthes et le théâtre", November 28, 1995; cuid18535 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0201)
  - Rubidge, Bradley: "The Code of Reciprocation in Corneille's Heroic Drama" (recorded by Michael), November 30, 1995; cuid18536 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0202)
  - Sonnenfeld, Albert: "New Orleans and the French Connection", December 5, 1995; cuid18537 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0203)
  - Lubar, Robert: "Unmasking Pablo's Gertrude: Queer Desire and the Origins of Cubism", December 7, 1995; cuid18538 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0204)
  - Mercer, Valérie: "African-American Artists in Paris: 1945-1965", January 30, 1996; cuid18539 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0205)
  - Irelé, Francis Abiola: "Léopold Sédar Senghor: A Revaluation", February 6, 1996; cuid18540 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0206)
    Duration: 48; Preservation Note: Side 2 is blank
  - Howard, Richard: "Baudelaire and Whitman: A Missed Opportunity", February 12, 1996; cuid18541 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0207)
    Duration: 81 minutes; Preservation Note: Side 1: 00:00:00;xx - 00:08:42;xx - Chatter before the start of the reading.
  - Federman, Raymond: "Lecture d'extraits de La Fourrure de ma tante Rachel", February 26, 1996; cuid18542 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0208)
  - Bury, Emmanuel, February 29, 1996; cuid18543 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0209)
    Duration: 91 minutes; Preservation Note: Side 2: 00:19:52;xx - 00:43:05;xx [END] is different and unrelated content. Captured for the master, but not included on the access copy.
  - Biet, Christian: "Tragique et tragédie classique", March 5, 1996; cuid18544 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0210)
  - Nicole, Eugène: "Retour à Saint Pierre", March 19, 1996; cuid18545 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0211)
  - Nancy, Jean-Luc: "Being with" (Florence Gould Lecture), April 9, 1996; cuid18546 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0212)
  - Lacoue-Labarthe, Philippe: "La Poétique de l'histoire" (Florence Gould Lecture, co-sponsored by the Department of German), April 11, 1996; cuid18547 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0213)
  - Ndiaye, Catherine: "Lecture de textes" (Co-sponsored with Africana Studies Program), April 16, 1996; cuid18548 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0214)
    Duration: 94 minutes; Preservation Note: Side 2 contains unrelated content with actress Charlotte Rae
  - Scarpetta, Guy: "Réflections sur la critique", April 18, 1996; cuid18549 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0215)
    Duration: 93 minutes; Preservation Note: Side 2: 00:00:00;xx - 00:03:37;xx is different (but possibly related) content. 00:03:37;xx - END appears to be a continuation of side 1.
  - Lacloche, Francis: "L'Etat, les villes, les entreprises: tous mécènes?", April 23, 1996; cuid18550 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0216)
    Duration: 96 minutes; Preservation Note: Side 2: at 00:29:56;xx New and unrelated content begins
  - Meddeb, Abdelwahab: "Dédale: Mondialité et transdisciplinarité", April 25, 1996; cuid18551 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0217)
    Duration: 70 minutes; Preservation Note: Side 2 has separate content
  - Le Dantec, Jean-Pierre: "La Nouvelle architecture française", April 29, 1996; cuid18552 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0218)
  - Bujon de L'Estang, François: "La France, L'Europe et le nouveau partenariat transatlantique", May 1, 1996; cuid18553 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0219)
  - Heinan, Eglal: "Lui ou elle: les travestissements masculins et féminins dans L'Astrée", September 19, 1996; cuid18554 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0220)
  - Manet, Eduardo: "Lecture de textes", October 7, 1996; cuid18555 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0221)
  - Genette, Gérard: "Combray-Venise-Combray", October 8, 1996; cuid18556 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0222)
    Duration: 35 minutes; Preservation Note: Side 2 is blank
  - Artaud Colloquium: "Delirious Anthropology", October 18, 1996
    - Audio recording, cuid18588 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0223)
      Duration: 88 minutes; Preservation Note: Electronic buzz throughout content
    - Audio recording, cuid18589 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0224)
      Duration: 64 minutes; Preservation Note: Electronic buzz throughout content
  - Gautrat, Patrick: "Les Grands axes de la politique étrangère de la France", October 22, 1996; cuid18557 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0225)
    Duration: 81 minutes
  - Ernaux, Annie: "Lecture de textes - Le Réel et l'intime", November 11, 1996; cuid18558 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0226)
  - Lestringant, Frank: "Argus à la sphère ou la mélancolie du cosmographe (XVIe siècle)", November 12, 1996; cuid18559 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0227)
  - Noël, Bernard: "Poésie et critique d'art", November 14, 1996; cuid18560 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0228)
  - Baudrillard, Jean: "L'Exponentielle et la masse critique" (Florence Gould Lecture), November 18, 1996; cuid18561 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0229)
  - Gengembre, Gérard: "Penser l'après-révolution: le moment 1800", November 19, 1996; cuid18562 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0230)
    Duration: 46 minutes; Preservation Note: Side 2 is blank
  - Salazar, Philippe Joseph: "Barthes et la séduction d'enseigner", November 21, 1996; cuid18563 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0231)
  - Peer, Shanny: "Tintin en Amérique: Popular Adventures in America Between the Wars", December 4, 1996; cuid18564 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0232)
  - Mainardi, Patricia: "Corot and Modernism", December 5, 1996; cuid18565 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0233)
  - Ivry, Benjamin, December 10, 1996; cuid18566 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0234)
  - Beaujour, Michel and Sieburth, Richard: "An evening of Maurice Scève", January 30, 1997; cuid18567 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0235)
  - Kaplan, Alice: "August 1944: Scenes from the Birth of Post- War France", February 3, 1997; cuid18568 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0236)
    Duration: 1 minute; Preservation Note: Side 1: Only 24 seconds of content, and with fluctuationg speed. Side 2 is blank. The tape split and had to be reassembled but it only affected blank area.
  - French Book Festival - Sollers, Philippe: "Introduction by Tom Bishop: L'Identité Française", September 8, 1997; cuid18569 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0237)
    Duration: 80 minutes; Preservation Note: Audio low
  - French Book Festival - Sollers, Philippe: Keynote lecture in French, September 8, 1997; cuid18570 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0238)
  - Zink, Michel: "Saint Bernard et la conversion du jongleur" (Florence Gould Lecture, co-sponsored by Medieval and Renaissance Studies Program), September 24, 1997; cuid18571 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0239)
  - Michon, Pierre: "Lectures de textes", October 2, 1997; cuid18572 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0240)
  - Roudinesco, Elisabeth: "Jacques Lacan; l'Histoire effacée" (French Theory in America Event), October 14, 1997; cuid18573 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0241)
  - Brombert, Victor: "Flaubert: Fiction, History, Revolution" (Andrew Dulau Lecture), October 21, 1997; cuid18574 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0242)
  - Dallenbach, Lucien: "La Mosaïque en art et littérature: de Balzac à Claude Simon", October 23, 1997; cuid18575 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0243)
  - Gaillard, Françoise: "On Barthes", October 27, 1997; cuid18576 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0244)
    Duration: 89 minutes; Preservation Note: Side 1: First 15 minutes has slightly muted sound. Side 2: First 13 minutes has slightly muted sound
  - Genette, Gérard: "Esquisse d'un parcours", November 3, 1997; cuid18577 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0245)
  - Nothomb, Amelie: "Lecture de textes", March 12, 1998; cuid18578 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0246)
  - Reut, Tita and Arman: "Lecture de poésie et dialogue entre le poète et l'artiste", February 26, 1999
    - Audio recording, cuid18590 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0247)
      Duration: 96 minutes; Preservation Note: Very low audio
    - Audio recording, cuid18591 (Box 10, Audiocassette 37-13.0248)
      Duration: 12 minutes; Preservation Note: Very low audio; Side 2 is blank
  - Sarraute Tribute at Maison Francaise, January 27, 2000
    - Audio recording, cuid18592 (Box 7, Audiocassette 37-13.0249)
    - Audio recording, cuid18593 (Box 7, Audiocassette 37-13.0250)
      Duration: 23 minutes; Preservation Note: Side 2 is blank